<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4001/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4001/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-05-28T08:42:28+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4001/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Caila’s Stuff</title><subtitle>A software engineer and motorbike fanatic. Sometimes she writes about bikes she&apos;s ridden and stuff she&apos;s working on for fun. </subtitle><author><name>Caila Finn</name></author><entry><title type="html">2022 Honda CMX500 Rebel Review</title><link href="http://localhost:4001/motorbikes/review/honda-cmx500-rebel/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Honda CMX500 Rebel Review" /><published>2024-05-20T13:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-05-20T13:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4001/motorbikes/review/honda-cmx500-rebel</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4001/motorbikes/review/honda-cmx500-rebel/"><![CDATA[<p><em>Honda have made the authentic cruiser experience accessible to everyone holding an A2 license… it’s just a shame that the experience sucks.</em></p>

<p>There’s a lot to like about the Rebel when you see it sat in the garage. The low seat hight is reassuring, allowing even the shortest riders to have their feet flat when sat on it. Its small size, low mass, and wide bars give plenty of leverage to bring the bike upright. The mid-board footpegs are perfectly placed above your feet and just where you would expect them to be as you pull away. Even the styling looks right. The round mirrors and big headlight look friendly. The high teardrop tank, low seat, fat tyres, and dual shocks put in a lot of work to make this very small bike look bigger than it is. Full-size, but without being intimidating.</p>

<p><img src="/images/IMG_4431.jpeg" alt="garage photo" /></p>

<p>The positive feelings continue when you get the engine going, as long as you’ve managed to work out that the steering lock and ignition switches are on opposite sides of the bike (c’mon Honda, was this to make the bike feel “authentic” or were you just being cheap?). Despite using the same 471cc, 47hp 180º p-twin from the rest of the CB500 range, Honda remapped the ECU to provide more low-end torque.  They also redesigned the muffler while transposing the engine from the Rebel’s sportier sisters. This provides a bit more of that cruiser growl off-idle… something the most boring engine configuration in modern motorcycling desperately needs to stand out. It certainly makes a better noise than the rest of the 500 range, but it’s still less interesting than if they’d put a 270º crank in there.</p>

<p>Chugging around town, the Rebel feels great. The increased low-end torque, the arms-out riding position, and the Rebel’s new voice provide a satisfying heave as you pull out of the garage or away from a set of lights, making the bike’s engine feel much stronger than it is. The wide handlebars make it effortless to flick around junctions, potholes, and traffic. The fat rear tyre, long rake, and cupped rear seat allow both bike and rider to feel supported and stable, so it never feels out of control either.</p>

<p>The Rebel’s strong start begins to falter on the open road, however. Probably thanks to their positioning, the pegs feel like they’re as wide as the handlebars when cornering. I’m no stranger to touching a peg to the ground when riding spiritedly, but almost every single roundabout causes the right-hand peg to scrape the tarmac. For sure, it’s entertaining the first few times when you’re out for fun, but it quickly gets tiresome when it has unsettled the rear four times during your commute to work. The brakes are also surprisingly awful. Less-than-perfect braking force isn’t uncommon in the A2 market, but the Rebel’s brakes are dreadful even for A2 bikes. The rear pedal feels like pressing down on a treacle-filled sponge and the front lever only vaguely feels like it’s connected to that single front disc brake. This is doubly confusing when compared with the brakes on the other Honda 500 models. Despite them being nothing to write home about, they are still leagues better than this.</p>

<p><img src="/images/IMG_4436.jpeg" alt="wales photo" /></p>

<p>I’ll be the first to admit that I’m the wrong shape for the Rebel. With an 82cm/32” inseam the footpegs are too high and the rubber grips on the frame too low for my knees to press against. This leaves only the teardrop tank as a grip point, which is <em>just</em> thin enough so that the clutch cover bullies my shins for space. Honda clearly knew this would be a problem, though. A thick, black, plastic heat-shield has been added over the clutch cover, which then takes up even more of the limited real estate caused by those mid-board footpegs being perfectly in-line with the motor. On the long ride home from Wales the Rebel quickly aggravated my back. The riding position made it almost impossible to stand and stretch without pulling myself up via the bars, which the bike did not like at all; wobbling angrily until I was sat down again. Fortunately, I didn’t have to stay in the seat for very long. The tank barely holds enough fuel for 90 miles before the 4-bar gauge starts flashing, forcing me to pull over for more fuel and a stretch to disentangle my vertebrae.</p>

<p>To sum up, the Rebel has its place in Honda’s line-up. They need something to bring in the newer, shorter, or less-confident rider so they can feel their way into the full-sized Rebel 1100 and other bigger bikes in their catalogue. It’s very possible cruisers just aren’t for me, and if you’re just going to use it around town you might find joy in its styling and accessibility. But unless you are one of the very newest or shortest riders, who need the confidence inspired by being able to flat foot your new machine, just buy any of the other Honda 500s and experience a much more comfortable, versatile, and enjoyable ride.</p>]]></content><author><name>Caila Finn</name></author><category term="Motorbikes" /><category term="Review" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Honda have made the authentic cruiser experience accessible to everyone holding an A2 license… it’s just a shame that the experience sucks.]]></summary></entry></feed>