<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-04-07T22:00:37+01:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Conor Finn</title><subtitle>I am a final year Computer Science student at the University of Kent in Canterbury.  I also spend a lot of time doing photography for both fun and work, and am just beginning to get into motorbikes.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Humble Beginnings</title><link href="/motorbikes/Humble-Beginnings/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Humble Beginnings" /><published>2021-04-02T19:27:39+01:00</published><updated>2021-04-02T19:27:39+01:00</updated><id>/motorbikes/Humble-Beginnings</id><content type="html" xml:base="/motorbikes/Humble-Beginnings/">&lt;p&gt;My first step to motorbike ownership… I have a CBT certificate! This tells my insurance company or a nosy police officer that I have completed the UK’s Compulsory Basic Training for motorcycle competence. This basically means that I’m slightly less likely to kill myself or others if I’m out on the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day began with meeting my instructor and the other person I’d be spending the day with, James. I was going to be riding a geared, 125cc Lexmoto ZSB motorbike, and he’d be on a 125cc scooter. We were then taken to the bikes and given some information on proper care and maintenance. This included two acronyms:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BEST COPS (done every week or so):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;B: Brakes&lt;br /&gt;
E: Electrics&lt;br /&gt;
S: Suspension&lt;br /&gt;
T: Tyres&lt;br /&gt;
C: Chain&lt;br /&gt;
O: Oil&lt;br /&gt;
P: Petrol&lt;br /&gt;
S: Steering&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and BOLTS (done before each ride):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;B: Brakes&lt;br /&gt;
O: Oil&lt;br /&gt;
L: Lights&lt;br /&gt;
T: Tyres&lt;br /&gt;
S: Steering&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that James, the other student, had already done the CBT and knew how to ride, I was then shown how to take the bike off its centre stand: Lean it back and push it forwards. Then I had to get it back on… It is at this moment I reach to grab the front brake, lean &lt;em&gt;slightly&lt;/em&gt; too far, and 125kg of motorbike overpowers 60kg of me and we both fall to the floor in a heap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welp… better my first drop happens to someone elses bike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the only damage being to my shins and my pride; we continue with some low speed manuevers, learning how to approach junctions, and how to use both the clutch and rear brake to control my speed (rather than the throttle).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, we go to lunch, do a bit of highway code study, and then it’s time to gear up for the road practice. We’re both on the receiving end of a one way radio from our instructor, who talks us through each manoeuver. We pulled over a few times to practice U-turns and emergency stops, and then headed out onto the more open roads. This is where I really wish James wasn’t on a scooter. I was desperate to open the taps and go for some corners. But when forced to follow a scooter that taps out at 33mph, it’s just not possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was on the country lanes that I fell in love. Even on the most uncomfortable seat in the world, I never wanted to stop. Opening the taps and hearing that exhaust note right behind you is such a rush.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would tell anyone who is confused by people who ride motorbikes to just book a CBT and give it a go. The instructors are usually delightful and really passionate. They’ll talk you through everything and make sure whatever you’re doing is safe and secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might just discover it’s the hobby you’ve always been waiting for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021-04-02/cbt_bikes.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Left to right: My Lexmoto ZSB, my instructor's Honda CB500F, and James' Lexmoto scooter (&amp;amp; James).&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align: center; padding: 5px;&quot;&gt;Left to right: My Lexmoto ZSB, my instructor's Honda CB500F, and James' Lexmoto scooter (&amp;amp; James).&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Motorbikes" /><summary type="html">My first step to motorbike ownership… I have a CBT certificate! This tells my insurance company or a nosy police officer that I have completed the UK’s Compulsory Basic Training for motorcycle competence. This basically means that I’m slightly less likely to kill myself or others if I’m out on the road.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First Post</title><link href="/general/first-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Post" /><published>2021-03-16T17:04:49+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-16T17:04:49+00:00</updated><id>/general/first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="/general/first-post/">&lt;p&gt;Suppose I should write something in here. Thought it might be a good place to keep track of my
various hobbies and interests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully I’ll be able to keep this up for a while, particularly for keeping track of my motorbike
stuff. Since it’s something I currently have no experience in it might be nice to come back to
this later and see how my skills have developed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s wait and see.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="General" /><summary type="html">Suppose I should write something in here. Thought it might be a good place to keep track of my various hobbies and interests.</summary></entry></feed>